JAVIER RAMIREZ

Software Engineer



<u>javier.rammez.iervao@gman.co</u>









Passionate software engineer dedicated to making a positive impact. With a global perspective gained from experiences in France and Spain, I have diverse expertise spanning CAD, automotive industry, security, and IoT. Presently employed at Dassault Systèmes in Lyon, France.

EXPERIENCE

Dassault Systemes / Software Engineer

08/2019-Present

Electrical System Design app inside the CATIA portfolio of the 3DExperience platform from Dassault Systemes. Development of an innovative app that empowers manufacturers to automatically generate networks and electrical schemas directly from 3D Mockups.

- C++ development for CAD and PLM applications to design electrical systems on Windows and Linux OS
- CI/CD processes and enhance workflow efficiency through the development of tools using Python and Bash scripting
- Develop UI elements utilizing web technologies to improve the user interface and overall user experience
- Draft detailed technical software specifications and plan strategies for unit testing
- Design software architecture with a primary focus on reusability, modular frameworks and enhanced flexibility
- Define models for Model-Based Systems Engineering (MBSE) to contribute to the engineering process

Continental / Software Engineer

01/2017-08/2019

ECU software development to control a Direct Injection Engine inside the new E-Power technology for Nissan (combination of an internal combustion engine with a battery-driven electric motor).

- Design of the system architecture for a real-time application. Focus on software reliability
- Software development on C/C++ code conforming the AUTOSAR standard and following MISRA C guidelines
- Python and Perl scripting to automate the creation of tests for both validation and non-regression purposes
- Task management: task tracking, technical guidance and support to fellow employees
- Develop a structured workflow for the internal code review process, supported by an automated system

Rockwell Collins / Software Engineer Intern

03/2016-09/2016

Security application to control cameras using the detections made by the radar FMWC PSR-500. The application featured a user-friendly interface for system parameterization and monitoring, incorporating versatile drivers tailored to various camera protocols.

- C++ development using the QT framework for Windows and Linux OS
- Plan and specify validation tests to ensure the quality and reliability of software
- Create software mock-ups tailored for customer demonstrations

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

ENSEEIHT (Ecole Nationale Supérieure d'Electrotechnique, d'Electronique, d'Informatique, d'Hydraulique et des Télécommunications) 2015 - 2016

Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

UPNA (Universidad Publica de Navarra) 2014 - 2015

Engineering degree. Electronic engineering

Universidad de La Rioja 2010 - 2014

SKILLS

Programming Languages	Software Applications	Technologies	Development Methods
C, C++ (C++ 11)	Visual Studio, QT IDE, Eclipse	Embedded systems	V Cycle, Agile
Python (3.0), Bash, Perl, VBS	Git, CMake	CAD, System Engineering	Object Oriented Programming, design Patterns, TDD
HTML, Javascript, CSS	CATIA, 3D Experience, Matlab	Real-Time, Multicore, AUTOSAR	CI/CD, Unit Testing, Automatic Testing

LANGUAGES

• Spanish(Native) • English(Full professional proficienty)

French(Full professional proficienty)